<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Fabiana's Page on Fabiana Ferracina</title><link>http://fabstat.github.io/</link><description>Recent content in Fabiana's Page on Fabiana Ferracina</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://fabstat.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fabiana's Page</title><link>http://fabstat.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fabstat.github.io/about/</guid><description>About Me I am a Ph.D. student at the Mathematics and Statistics Department of Washington State University. My research interests are broad, ranging from applying state-space models to ecological problems to topological data analysis (TDA).
Currently, I am working with my advisor Bala Krishnamoorthy on the application of TDA tools to problems in artificial and biological neural networks. My goal is to gain structural insight on how both machines and humans use input to make decisions, in order to better understand learning in these two settings.</description></item><item><title>Fabiana's Research</title><link>http://fabstat.github.io/research/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fabstat.github.io/research/</guid><description>source: Wikipedia Topological data analysis (TDA) is a subfield of algebraic topology whose application to areas of study outside mathematics is becoming more and more common. Two such areas of interest to me are neuroscience and computer science. In neuroscience, TDA has been applied to EEG signals, fMRI data and connectomes to study both implicit and explicit topological structures of brain states and function. In computer science, specifically in the fields of machine learning and networks, TDA has been used to both take the topology of the input data into account in order to inform models, as well as to incorporate topological information directly into the design of models.</description></item><item><title>Fabiana's Teaching Experience</title><link>http://fabstat.github.io/teaching/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fabstat.github.io/teaching/</guid><description>Teaching is an important aspect of my life as a graduate student at WSU Vancouver. I also taught math and computer science classes as a lecturer at the University of Washington Bothell.
WSU MATH 106: College Algebra (class) WSU MATH 140: Calculus for Life Scientists (lab) WSU MATH 171: [QUAN] Calculus I (both class and labs) WSU STAT 212: [QUAN] Introduction to Statistical Methods (class) WSU STAT 360: Probability and Statistics (class - my slides) WSU STAT 380: [M] Decision Making and Statistics (grading) WSU Quantitative Skills Center Math, Stats and R Tutoring UW Bothell BCUSP 122/123: Functions, Models, and Quantitative Reasoning UW Bothell BCUSP 124/125: Calculus I and II UW Bothell BCUSP 127: Learning Strategies in Mathematics UW Bothell CSS 161/SKL 161: Fundamentals of Computing (class and lab) UW Bothell CSS 162: Programming Methodology UW Bothell CSS 490 Electives: Introduction to Functional Programming; and Elements of Scientific Computing (designed and taught)</description></item></channel></rss>